Are you getting used to living here?
住在这里还习惯吗?
Yes.
什么?
What do you do during the day?
你白天都做什么打发时间?
Don't you have too much free time if housework is all you do?
除了家务外 应该还有许多剩余时间吧?
Well...
那个...
I read magazines Ms. Yurie lends me, and I sew some things.
我从由里江阿姨那借杂志来看 或是做些针线活
Actually, I'm thinking of going into town this weekend.
这次假期我打算出门
All right. What should I do about preparing your lunch and supper?
好的 午饭和晚饭您打算怎么办呢?
You're coming too. We're going together.
你要跟我一起去
Pardon?
什么?
You haven't been to town once since you came here, have you?
你来这里还一次没去过镇上吧?
That's true.
是
Don't you want to go?
你不想去吗?
Um...
我不知道
What?
什么?
I can't go.
我不能去
I don't have a reason to go, and I'll be a bother to you.
我没有理由去 而且会给你添麻烦
You won't be a bother, and you don't need a reason to go.
并没有 而且不需要理由也可以去
B-But won't I be in the way?
但我会不会妨碍到你?
You won't be in the way at all.
不会的
You can wear the same furisode you wore when you came here.
衣服就穿你来时那件就行
Is anything else worrying you?
还有其他问题吗?
No.
没有了
Be ready to go, then.
那就这么定了
Thanks for the meal.
我吃好了
Sir...
老爷
At that moment
那时
I didn't have any idea what my husband-to-be was thinking.
我还完全不了解老爷的想法
Thus, our first date was suddenly scheduled.
“第一次约会”就这样 唐突地决定下来了
MY HAPPY MARRIAGE
剧名:我的幸福婚约
EPISODE 3 OUR FIRST DATE
第3集:第一次约会
Ms. Miyo, may I come in?
美世小姐 我可以进来吗?
Y-Yes, please.
请进
How are your preparations going, Ms. Miyo?
你准备得怎么样了 美世小姐?
Um, fine.
好了
Please don't hesitate to use this mirror.
请尽情使用这面镜子
How ill-matched we are.
我们一点都不相配
Ms. Miyo?
美世小姐?
Wouldn't you like to put on some makeup?
您不化妆吗?
I... I haven't tried using makeup so much.
我没怎么化过妆
Oh, then leave it up to me.
那就交给我吧
B-But I don't own any makeup or tools.
但是我没有化妆工具
You don't have to worry. Here.
不用担心 你瞧
I have all the tools you need.
工具都在这里呢
This is so nice.
真好
Although I don't have anything new and fancy,
虽然没有什么时髦的东西
I'm sure this would look beautiful on you.
这个肯定很适合你
I'll start applying the face powder,
那么我给你扑粉了
so would you please close your eyes for a bit?
请你闭上眼睛可以吗?
There. It's done.
好了 化好了
I wonder how Young Master will react
看到这么漂亮的美世小姐
when he sees how pretty you are, Ms. Miyo.
少爷会作何反应呢?
Are you about ready yet?
准备好了吗?
I'll be right there.
我马上就来
Pardon me for keeping you waiting.
让您久等了
Sir?
老爷?
Uh, no. You didn't keep me waiting.
我没等多久
Sorry to have rushed you.
不该催你的 抱歉
It's all right.
没什么
Shall we go?
走吧?
Yes.
好的
Sir, where are we going today?
请问今天要去哪里?
Oh, didn't I tell you? We're going to my workplace first.
没告诉你吗?先去我工作的地方
Huh?
什么?
Don't get so nervous. I'm just parking the car there before we go into town.
不用这么紧张 去镇上之前 要把车停到那
So this is where he works...
这就是老爷工作的地方
Let's go now.
我们走吧
Yes.
好的
Could it be?
这不是...
Godo.
五道
So it is you, Commander.
是你啊 队长
Aren't you off duty today?
你今天不是休息吗?
Yeah, I just came to park my car here.
对 我只是来停车的
Oh, I see.
这样啊
And, who might this be?
这位是?
My companion. Don't pry into my private life.
我带的人 不要打听我的私事
And such a beautiful companion at that.
而且还是这么漂亮的女孩子
Hey.
喂
I said don't pry into my private life. Didn't you hear me?
我说了不要让你打听 你没听见吗?
Oops. Excuse me.
是我失礼了
Stop fooling around and get back to your post right now.
不要在这里磨蹭了 回到你自己的岗位上去
Yes, sir! Have a nice day, sir.
遵命 您辛苦了
Good grief...
真是的
He's my close aide, Godo.
他是我的亲信 叫五道
Despite his behavior, he does have superior supernatural abilities...
虽然看起来不靠谱 但是作为异能者很出色
although I'm reluctant to admit it.
虽然我很不愿意承认
Okay. Is there anywhere you want to go?
好了 你有没有想去的地方?
Huh?
什么?
Don't you have something you need or want to buy?
有想买的或者想要的东西吗?
N-No.
不
Nothing in particular...
没有什么特别想要的
What should I do? I can't think of anything I want at all.
怎么办?我根本没有什么想要的
Nothing?
没有?
Then, you should accompany me for my shopping.
那就陪我去买东西吧
Certainly.
好的
Are you enjoying yourself?
你开心吗?
I-I'm sorry.
对不起
I shouldn't have gotten so enamored with the scenery...
我不小心入迷了
Don't worry about it. You can enjoy the scenery all you want.
不用在意 尽情享受就好
Nobody here disapproves, including me.
不管是我还是旁人 都不会怪罪你的
But...
但是...
You don't have to think about causing any inconvenience.
你也不用担心会给我添麻烦
I'm the one who asked you to come into town with me.
是我让你来的 不是别人 是我
Got it?
明白吗?
Yes.
好的
Just pay attention and don't get lost.
不要左顾右盼走散了就好
I'll be careful.
我会小心
Good.
好
How is he rumored to be a cold and merciless man?
这个人哪里冷酷无情了?
Look at how kind he is.
他这么温柔
We had a deal, didn't we?
这和我们说好的不一样
What deal?
我们说好什么了?
Don't play dumb! Why did you give Miyo to the Kudo family?
别装傻 为什么你把美世送去久堂家?
I asked you to let her marry our eldest son.
我拜托过你 让你把她嫁给我的长子
Oh, that deal.
那件事啊
At the same time, we had a marriage offer from the Kudo family we couldn't refuse.
正好久堂家来求亲 我们不能拒绝
Miyo's mother is from that Usuba family.
美世的母亲是薄刃家的人
But Miyo didn't inherit supernatural abilities.
但是她没有继承异能
Even so, Miyo might have children who inherit supernatural abilities.
就算如此 美世的孩子 也有可能继承了薄刃的异能
You're that desperate to obtain the Usuba family's powers, aren't you?
你就这么想要薄刃的力量吗?
You know the Usuba family's powers are said to be exceptional!
薄刃的异能 在异能者中也是非常特别的
If the Kudo family gets even more powerful, our positions will be in danger.
放任久堂家壮大会威胁到我们的地位
Kudo will surely get rid of Miyo when he finds out she doesn't have abilities.
知道美世没有异能的话 久堂家很快就会抛弃她
When that happens, you can go ahead and bring her into your family.
到那时 你们再收留她吧
She'd be thankful and crying with joy if you picked her up.
如果你们收留她 美世会感激涕零吧
No matter how much he loves his younger daughter,
就算他再怎么宠爱幼女
he must be insane to want to abandon Miyo.
也不能就这样放弃美世
Miyo could be the goose that lays the golden eggs.
那可是说不定会下金蛋的母鸡
So are we in agreement that the Saimori family will have no say in Miyo's future?
那今后无论美世有何遭遇 斋森家都不许置喙
Yes. We basically abandoned that child.
好 我们不要她了
I'm not interested in her future, regardless of whether she lives or dies.
对她在哪里、做什么 是生是死都不在意
I see. Understood.
这样啊 我知道了
It will be us, the Tatsuishi family, that will have Miyo Saimori as our own.
我们辰石家会得到美世
I'm not letting the Kudo family take her from us.
怎么能让久堂家夺走
Hey, you.
我说你
Y-Yes.
是
What's Father talking about with him?
父亲们在说什么
I don't know the details, but it seems they are discussing Ms. Miyo.
我不清楚 似乎是美世小姐的事
What?
什么?
Why did Big Sister's name come up?
为什么会出现姐姐的名字?
I-I'm sorry, Ms. Kaya.
对不起
Kaya, you shouldn't raise your voice like that.
香耶 不要这么大声
Koji, are you trying to lecture me?
幸次 你是在教训我吗?
Why do Father and Mr. Tatsuishi have to talk about Big Sister now?
事到如今 父亲和辰石大人 为什么会谈到姐姐?
Don't let it bother you so much.
不要这么说
I know! Since it's such a nice day, why don't we go out shopping?
对了 香耶 难得天气这么好 你不想去买东西吗?
That department store opened last week. Didn't you want to go?
你不是想去上周开张的商场吗?
I guess we could go. There's nothing else to do anyway.
好吧 反正我们没什么事
There's a new shop in Nakamichi.
仲道有一家新店
I heard the shop has...
我听说店里...
Koji probably still has feelings for Big Sister.
幸次现在肯定还想着姐姐
For all we know, she might already be dead at the Kudo family residence.
说不定她已经死在久堂家里了
SUZUSHIMAYA KIMONO SHOP
(铃岛屋吴服店)
This shop is called Suzushimaya.
这里是铃岛屋
Our Kudo family has been their loyal customer for years.
与久堂家常年来往的店
I heard they've made garments for the Emperor.
听说他们还负责圣上的衣物
That is very impressive.
好棒的店
Welcome to our shop, Mr. Kudo.
欢迎光临 久堂先生
I need your help today.
今天就拜托你了
We've already selected some fabrics based on your request.
您之前说到的衣服 我已经选出几件符合要求的
Please come inside.
请进
Right.
好
Mr. Kudo, I see you've finally...
久堂先生 我听说您终于决定下来了
It's not what it seems, really.
并不是这样
You don't have to be embarrassed.
不用这么害羞
You've never brought a lady here before.
您是第一次带女性来这里
Well, that is true. But...
确实是这样 不过...
Young Master, have you noticed?
少爷 你知道吗?
Ms. Miyo seems to be mending her old clothes herself.
美世小姐自己缝补旧衣
I was going to say something, but I don't think she wanted us to know.
我想同她说话 但是她好像不想让别人知道
She wears worn-out clothes like a poor rural farmer.
她穿着破旧的衣服 如同乡野农民一般
Probably the only proper kimono she has is the one she's wearing now.
恐怕她完好的衣服 只有现在穿的这一件
She hardly owns anything that a girl of her age
她几乎没有与她年龄相称
who comes from a prominent family should have.
身为名门之女 理所当然拥有的东西
Mr. Kudo.
久堂先生
Oh, excuse me.
抱歉
What would look good on her?
她适合什么样的?
I think that soft colors like these would suit the lady.
我想这种浅色更适合她
Also these, and in these combinations.
还有这些 这种组合也很不错
How about that one?
那件呢?
That's a very fine fabric, too.
那也是上好的布料
But it takes a while to tailor the kimono, so the season might be a little off.
但是现在缝制的话 上身的时候或许与时节不符
I see.
这样啊
It would be perfect... on her.
应该很合适她
What would you prefer?
你觉得怎么样?
Uh, yes.
这样啊
Make one with this.
就用这个
And also some using the selections you made would be nice.
然后麻烦你再做几件其他衣服
Very well, sir.
明白了
How about this?
这个
Do you want to take this home today?
您今天带回家吗?
Yes. I'll take it now.
嗯 我拿走了
By the way, Mr. Kudo.
请问 久堂先生
What is it?
怎么了?
Don't ever let go of that lady.
绝对不要放走那个女孩
She's like a diamond in the rough
她是原石
with a myriad of opportunities to shine.
潜力不可估量
The items you bought today are only the beginning.
今天买的东西只是开始
With your love and wealth, you must polish her and never let her go.
您要用爱与财富不断地打磨 不要让她离开
And then...
总有一天...
And then?
总有一天?
You'll have the enjoyment of dressing a beautiful lady without hesitation!
您会毫无顾虑地享受打扮美人的乐趣
Oh... Good lord.
真是的
Mother.
母亲
SWEETS SHOP
(甜品店)
How is it?
怎么样?
Um, it's good.
那个 很好吃
Your expression doesn't really say so.
你的表情不像是好吃
I-I do think so.
我真的觉得好吃
I never see you smile.
我从没见你笑过
Oh. I'm sorry.
对不起
No, I'm not accusing you.
我不是指责你
It's just that...
只是...
I kind of want to see you smile a little.
我想看到你笑一下
Oh?
什么?
Sir, I think you are a bit strange.
老爷您很奇怪呢
Please forgive me for saying something brazen.
对不起 我说话唐突
I'm not angry at you at all.
我没有生气
So don't cower like that.
所以你也不用这么畏缩
But...
但是...
You and I
我们
are supposed to get married if all goes well.
这样下去会结婚的
I think it's better if we are able to say whatever we want.
所以还是畅所欲言的好
I'll be happier if you express your honest opinions to me,
我希望你能说出你真实的想法
instead of apologies.
而不是道歉
Supposed to get married...
结婚...
He probably still doesn't know
他肯定不知道
that I don't have supernatural abilities. I must tell him myself someday.
我并没有异能 总有一天我要告诉他
But now I can't help but hope.
但是我希望
I'm hoping I can stay with him as long as I can.
能多和他在一起
I'll accept any punishment for it later.
之后受到什么惩罚都可以
So please, let this last a little longer until I can take responsibility.
拜托了 再久一点 直到我能下定决心的那一天
Until that day...
直到那一天
Oh, Young Master. Ms. Miyo is taking a bath.
少爷 美世小姐在洗澡
Yurie, why are you still here?
由里江 你还没回去吗?
"Still here?" Isn't that a bit rude?
“还没回去”真是伤人
What is that?
那是什么?
S-Sir!
老爷
Is this...?
这是?
Settle down and just accept it.
你就老实收下吧
I can't accept such an expensive gift.
不能收这么贵重的东西
There's nothing to worry about.
不用在意
But...
但是...
Sir...
老爷
It was you who put it there, right?
是你放在那里的吗?
A comb as a gift has the meaning of a marriage proposal.
送发梳意味着求婚
This one doesn't mean anything special.
没有什么特殊含义
You're asking her to marry you, aren't you?
您是求婚了吗?
It's only a comb. I'm saying it doesn't mean anything.
只是一把梳子 没有特殊含义
Of course, you're right.
这样啊
Ms. Miyo has been using a half-broken comb.
美世小姐用的是一把快坏掉的梳子
Young Master giving her a new comb at this time is nothing special.
您现在送给她一把新梳子也不奇怪
Ms. Miyo is different from any other woman who has come to this house.
美世小姐和至今以来的女性都不一样
I can't agree with you more, Young Master.
我非常赞成 少爷
Like I said, it doesn't mean that...
我说了 没有特殊的...
I'm sure Ms. Miyo will be very happy.
美世小姐肯定会很高兴
Anyway, just go ahead and use it.
总之不用在意 用就好了
Thank you very much, sir.
谢谢您 老爷
I'll take good care of it while I'm using it.
我会小心使用
I guess it's a common domestic squabble in a family of supernatural abilities.
总之应该是常见的异能家族的那点事
Nevertheless, it's excessive.
即便如此 也不寻常
At least it's not behavior expected from a prominent family.
至少不是名门的做派
Kanoko Saimori, her stepmother, must have held a huge grudge.
她的继母斋森香乃子应该非常恨她
She and Shinichi Saimori were lovers, but his family forced him to marry
她和斋森真一曾是恋人 但男人却被家族逼迫
and have a child with another woman.
娶了另一个女人 并育有一女
They were the worst parents.
他们是最差劲的父母
What about the main issue?
那么进入正题吧
Yeah. As you assumed, Miyo Saimori doesn't have supernatural abilities.
正如您预料的那样 斋森美世没有异能
But her sister Kaya already had Spirit-Sight when she was three.
但是她的妹妹香耶在三岁时 已经有见鬼之才
That was probably when they started to treat Miyo, the elder sister, badly.
作为长女的美世境遇变差 恐怕也是从此开始的
Oppressed by her stepmother and younger sister,
虐待自己的继母和妹妹
without love from her birth father.
对自己毫无爱怜的父亲
She grew up all alone in that family.
就这样孤身一人吗?
I bet buying her a new kimono is not nearly enough to heal
我想给她买衣服并不足以抚平
the wounds of her heart.
她内心的伤口
Oh, by the way,
对了
there's one thing that concerns me.
有一件事我很在意
Shinichi's first wife, the birth mother of Miyo Saimori
关于斋森真一的前妻 斋森美世的生母
apparently came from the Usuba family.
貌似是薄刃家的人
What?
什么?
It was surprising. I didn't think the Usuba family actually existed.
我也吓了一跳 我以为薄刃家已经不存在了
The Usuba family bloodline has the supernatural ability
说起薄刃家 他们的异能是可以
to interfere with the human mind.
干涉人心
Is that information accurate?
消息确切吗?
Yeah.
是
Miyo Saimori's mother's name was Sumi Usuba.
斋森美世的母亲的名字是薄刃澄美
I couldn't find out how she entered into the Saimori family.
我没找到她是因为什么进了斋森家
Good grief... I truly feel like I'm not myself
真是的 从她来了
ever since she arrived.
我都不对劲起来
How foolish. Such nonsense.
真是愚蠢 做这种无用功
These are mere simple shiki-gami.
派这种简单的式神
Who could possibly be behind this?
但究竟是何方神圣所为?